<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Yuanyi Mao</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-02-09T15:46:52.172Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>John Doe</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to identify innovative and interesting research questions?</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/09/question/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/09/question/</id>
    <published>2020-02-09T12:43:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-09T15:46:52.172Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/2020/02/09/question/idea2.jpg" alt></p><p>I co-authored a short guide book with my master supervisor on academic thesis writing, where encompassing the whole steps of academic research, such as finding research questions, research design, statistical analysis and thesis construction. In this blog, I would like to summarize some materials that I collected and hope it to inspire more people. This part corresponds to Chapter 3: How to identify research questions.  </p><p><font color="red">A good research question is the half battle of an academic thesis.</font> Thus, we cannot emphasize too much the importance of an innovative and interesting question. </p><h5 id="1-What-is-an-interesting-question-or-theory"><a href="#1-What-is-an-interesting-question-or-theory" class="headerlink" title="1. What is an interesting question or theory"></a>1. What is an interesting question or theory</h5><p><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/004839317100100211?journalCode=posa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Davis (1971)</a> has a fantastic description of what is an interesting question, because he thinks “<em>a theorist is considered great, not because his theories are true, but because they are interesting</em>”. Thus, what are interesting theories look like? He unpacked the components of interesting propositions and gave us an abstract formulation:</p><table><tr><td bgcolor="yellow">“What seems to be X is in reality non- X” or “What is accepted as X is actually non-X”.</td></tr></table><p>That is to say:   </p><p>(Ⅰ) Articulate what we have been agree with or taken for granted   </p><p>(Ⅱ) Deny what we have been traditionally accepted   </p><p>(Ⅲ) Verify the old propositions are wrong and prove your new ones are right   </p><p>(Ⅳ) Figure out the future directions on how to employ these new propositions.    </p><p><img src="/2020/02/09/question/idea3.jpg" alt></p><h5 id="2-Where-could-we-identify-these-research-questions"><a href="#2-Where-could-we-identify-these-research-questions" class="headerlink" title="2. Where could we identify these research questions?"></a>2. Where could we identify these research questions?</h5><p>Research questions mainly come from two sources: from <strong><em>existing literature</em></strong>, <strong><em>daily life experiences</em></strong> (observations; chat with others; personal experiences). In this part, we will first talk about how to formulate research questions from the existing literature.</p><p><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1350508410372151" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sandberg and Alvesson (2011)</a> developed a typology of how scholar identify research questions from existing literature. He pointed out that spotting gaps in previous literature was the most frequently used approaches. Specifically, several gap-spotting modes are identified, I would take recent literature in communication as examples.  In most cases, scholars might combine different gap-spotting strategies to form research questions.</p><h6 id="2-1-Confusing-spotting-find-competing-explanations"><a href="#2-1-Confusing-spotting-find-competing-explanations" class="headerlink" title="2.1 Confusing spotting: find competing explanations"></a>2.1 Confusing spotting: find competing explanations</h6><p>“<em>Despite the evidence for partisan selective exposure, questions remain about the causal mechanisms that underlie the phenomenon. <font color="red">Many studies have employed cognitive dissonance theory</font> as a causal explanation (…) <font color="red">An alternative explanation</font> for partisan selective exposure comes from news consumers’ evaluations of the credibility of a news source and/or the information within news stories.</em>”    </p><h6 id="2-2-Neglect-spotting-find-an-overlooked-area"><a href="#2-2-Neglect-spotting-find-an-overlooked-area" class="headerlink" title="2.2 Neglect spotting: find an overlooked area"></a>2.2 Neglect spotting: find an overlooked area</h6><p>“<em>Prior research has revealed that young people’s exposure to mass media leads to stronger materialism through cultivation processes . (…) Surprisingly, <font color="red">little is known</font> about how <font color="red">young people’s use of SNSs</font> is associated with their consumption experience and materialism.</em>“  </p><p>“<em>A few studies have examined the effects of visual cues in crisis communication, such as a spokesperson’s race, facial features, or the use of powerful gestures. <font color="red">Research on vocal cues in crisis communication, however, is limited</font> to one study that examined the impact of only one vocal cue (voice pitch) on the perceptions of a spokesperson.</em>“  </p><h6 id="2-3-Neglect-spotting-add-additional-factors"><a href="#2-3-Neglect-spotting-add-additional-factors" class="headerlink" title="2.3 Neglect spotting: add additional factors"></a>2.3 Neglect spotting: add additional factors</h6><p>“<em>Furthermore, both expectation states and role congruity theories predict that status differentiation is most robust… However, this work was focused on the effects of linguistic style (i.e., speech assertiveness vs. tentativeness) on influence; <font color="red">researchers have yet</font> to consider how <font color="red">identity salience</font> moderates the effect of nonverbal behaviors on social influence.</em>“  </p><h6 id="2-4-Application-spotting-Extend-and-complement-existing-literature"><a href="#2-4-Application-spotting-Extend-and-complement-existing-literature" class="headerlink" title="2.4 Application spotting: Extend and complement existing literature"></a>2.4 Application spotting: Extend and complement existing literature</h6><p>“<em>Statistical models exist to quantify this part of social interaction, such as the actor-partner interdependence model (APIM; Kenny, Kashy, &amp; Cook, 2006), <font color="red">but such models have rarely been applied in this area.</font></em>“  </p><h6 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference:"></a>Reference:</h6><p>Davis, M. S. (1971). <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/004839317100100211?journalCode=posa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">That’s interesting! Towards a phenomenology of sociology and a sociology of phenomenology</a>. <em>Philosophy of the social sciences</em>, <em>1</em>(2), 309-344.</p><p>Sandberg, J., &amp; Alvesson, M. (2011). <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1350508410372151" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ways of constructing research questions: gap-spotting or problematization?</a>. <em>Organization</em>, <em>18</em>(1), 23-44.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2020/02/09/question/idea2.jpg&quot; alt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I co-authored a short guide book with my master supervisor on academic thesis writi
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Comments on review paper of moral psychology</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/01/review/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/01/review/</id>
    <published>2020-02-01T13:56:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-09T15:46:35.016Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/2020/02/01/review/moral.jpg" alt></p><p>I am grateful to <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1088868318811759" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ellemers, van der Toorn, Paunov, &amp; van Leeuwen’s (2019)</a> critical and comprehensive review paper. They analyzed a total of 1,278 relevant research articles from 1940 to 2017, which capture the whole picture of the development of moral psychology. This roadmap helps me reach a deeper insight into the topics of <strong>moral reasoning, moral emotion, moral judgment, moral behavior and moral self-views</strong>. From my side, I would like to summarize the future agenda in the “future direction” section of this paper and contribute my own ideas to this field of area.    </p><h5 id="1-The-relationship-between-moral-cognition-and-moral-behavior"><a href="#1-The-relationship-between-moral-cognition-and-moral-behavior" class="headerlink" title="1. The relationship between moral cognition and moral behavior"></a>1. The relationship between moral cognition and moral behavior</h5><p>First, they pointed out that there are not many studies focusing on how people’s <font color="blue">moral reasoning or moral judgment affects their moral behaviors</font>. That is to say “<em>we know much less about how this affects their moral behavior (p.354)</em>”.   </p><p>I strongly agree with this statement. I remembered two years before, when I jumped into this field, I found we have accumulated many studies on moral judgment and moral reasoning, but we still knew little about how these impact on people’s moral behaviors. Just as <a href="https://psyarxiv.com/wcsq6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nilsson, Erlandsson, and Vastfjall (2018)</a> stated in the article:  </p><p>“ <em>Despite these empirical successes, there is still <font color="rgb()">remarkably little research on the applicability of Moral Foundations Theory to real moral behavior</font>. The vast majority of past studies of moral intuitions have relied on self-report measures of moral attitudes and behaviors rather than <font color="rgb()">behavioral data</font>, partly due to a traditional split between the study of moral judgment and the study of moral behavior in the field. This is a crucial drawback</em>.”   </p><p>Fortunately, I found some research tried to examine the gaps. For example, the leading theory in the field of media and morality, <strong>“MIME (Model of Intuitive Morality and Exemplars)”</strong> <a href="https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/e/9780203127070/chapters/10.4324/9780203127070-11" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(Tamborini, 2012)</a>, emphasized that individual’s exposure to media content depicting moral domains influences people’s the accessibility of moral intuitions, which in turn affect subsequent moral decision making (e.g., selective exposure to liked media content). I feel that if the behavioral outcomes could be extended to general moral behaviors (e.g., donation, helping, caring, etc.), the model’s generalization and applicability would increase.  Also, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-13909-9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Francis et al (2017)</a> also investigated participant’s simulated moral actions when faced with moral dilemmas in visually immersive environments (Virtue Reality).  </p><p>At the same time, the authors emphasized that previous research neglected to examine how <font color="blue">abstract and general moral principles </font> are translated into guiding <font color="blue">specific moral actions</font>.   </p><p><img src="/2020/02/01/review/trooy.jpg" alt></p><h5 id="2-Different-research-levels"><a href="#2-Different-research-levels" class="headerlink" title="2. Different research levels"></a>2. Different research levels</h5><p>Second, the authors found most of the empirical research relating to morality takes <strong>intrapersonal and interpersonal approaches</strong>, relatively little studies have addressed the <strong><em>intragroup and intergroup mechanism</em></strong> in the field of morality. For example, how an individual’s <font color="blue">shared identities and group-specific moral norms</font> affecting their group-level moral behaviors and moral reasoning have been underexplored.  </p><h5 id="3-New-types-of-measurements"><a href="#3-New-types-of-measurements" class="headerlink" title="3. New types of measurements"></a>3. New types of measurements</h5><p>Finally, they asserted that new types of measurement such as <font color="blue">implicit indicators or physiological approaches</font> are needed because scholars have over-relied on using self-reported behavioral intention and explicit judgments. This is an interesting statement when people make moral judgements by using self-reported methods, their answers might be influenced by <strong>social desirability</strong>. To avoid the motivational bias, I found several scholars have tried to address this problem. For example, <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2016-41834-001" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tamborini et al (2018)</a> modified affect misattribution procedure (AMP) to develop the <strong>Moral Foundation-AMP</strong> to assess participant’s immediate moral intuition change.     </p><h6 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference:"></a>Reference:</h6><p>Ellemers, N., van der Toorn, J., Paunov, Y., &amp; van Leeuwen, T. (2019). <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1088868318811759" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The psychology of morality: A review and analysis of empirical studies published from 1940 through 2017</a>. <em>Personality and Social Psychology Review</em>, <em>23</em>(4), 332-366.  </p><p>Francis, K. B., Terbeck, S., Briazu, R. A., Haines, A., Gummerum, M., Ganis, G., &amp; Howard, I. S. (2017). <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-13909-9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Simulating moral actions: An investigation of personal force in virtual moral dilemmas</a>. <em>Scientific reports</em>, <em>7</em>(1), 1-11.  </p><p>Nilsson, A., Erlandsson, A., &amp; Vastfjall, D. (2018, June 18). <a href="https://psyarxiv.com/wcsq6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Moral foundations theory and the psychology of charitable giving</a>. osf.  </p><p>Tamborini, R. (2012). <a href="https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/e/9780203127070/chapters/10.4324/9780203127070-11" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A model of intuitive morality and exemplars</a>. In <em>Media and the moral mind</em> (pp. 67-98). Routledge.  </p><p>Tamborini, R., Prabhu, S., Lewis, R. J., Grizzard, M., &amp; Eden, A. (2018). <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2016-41834-001" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The influence of media exposure on the accessibility of moral intuitions and associated affect</a>. <em>Journal of Media Psychology: Theories, Methods, and Applications</em>, <em>30</em>(2), 79-90.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2020/02/01/review/moral.jpg&quot; alt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1088868318811
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
